# Agustin Guerra

888-858-6716 | agustinguerra@ufl.edu | LinkedIn | Portfolio

#### Professional Profile

Highly motivated engineering professional with 5+ years of experience in the transportation industry. Committed to providing high-quality service focusing on innovation, safety, sustainability, operational performance, diversity, equity, and inclusion. Currently seeking job opportunities in Transportation Engineering.

## **EDUCATION**

PhD candidate in Civil Engineering

Aug. 2019 – Expected May 2023

 $University\ of\ Florida$ 

Gainesville, FL

MS in Civil Engineering

Aug. 2017 – May 2019

University of Kansas

Lawrence, KS

BS in Civil Engineering

Mar. 2008 - May 2013

Universidad Tecnologica de Panama

Panama, PA

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Expertise: Transportation Engineering, Statistical Analysis, Operation Research, Machine Learning

Languages: Python (Proficient), R (Intermediate)

Software: VISSIM, HCS, AutoCAD Civil 3D, Infraworks, Slide-Rockscience

Developer Tools: Github, Visual Studio Libraries: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, CPLEX

# EXPERIENCE

#### Graduate Research Assistant

Aug. 2019 - Present

University of Florida

Gainesville, FL

- Develop optimization algorithms in Python for arterials considering automated-vehicles capabilities
- Assist in the implementation of optimization algorithm for isolated intersections
- Facilitated the coordination of project activities to meet deadlines
- Explained traffic flow theory assignments to students

## Highway & Traffic Consultant

May 2019 - Aug. 2019

WSP

Panama

- Provided safety assessment for roadways, interchanges, and intersections
- Developed geometric design proposals
- Conducted earthwork estimation for highway projects

#### **Highway Engineer**

Nov. 2012 – Aug. 2017

 $Louis\ Berger$ 

Panama

- Developed geometric designs for proposal and as-built drawings for highway projects. Project portfolio comprises several projects in the Latin American region (Panama, Colombia, Honduras, and Peru) adding up to \$3 billion in construction amount
- Coordinated with different departments (geotechnical, hydraulic, and pavement) to meet deadlines
- Created digital model terrain for highway projects
- Verified slope stability analysis using the Slide-Rockscience software
- Supervised and mentored drafter team with 4 people

#### Leadership/Involvement & Awards

ELIMBERGIIII / IIVVOEVEMENT & TIVITEDS	
ITE University Chapter Vice President: Coordinated student seminars and $\underline{\text{ITE}}$ activities	2021 - 2022
Student Representative at the UFTI Internal Steering <u>Committee</u> : Promoted engagement activities between industry professionals and students	2020 - 2022
ITS Florida Anne Brewer Academic Scholarships: Awarded by the $\underline{\text{ITS}}$ Florida Chapter	2022
Fulbright Fellowship: Awarded by the U.S Bureau of Educational and Cultural	2017 Affairs

Global Best Project: Awarded by the ENR for the Coastal Beltway project in Panama

2015

# 4th Bridge over the Panama Canal | Panama 2019 • Provided visibility and safety assessment for intersections and roadways • Developed geometric design alternatives for interchanges • Construction cost: \$1.2 billions Corredor Panama Norte | Panama 2016 • Played a major role in the coordination of the project • Developed design drawings and calculations including 3D models of roadways, roundabouts, and interchanges • Provided earthworks estimation Perimetral Oriental de Bogota | Colombia 2015 • Coordinated with other departments (geotechnical, hydraulic, surveying) to meet deadlines Developed design drawings and calculations including 3D models of roadways, intersections, and interchanges • Trained and supervised drafter team • Construction cost: \$428.0 millions 2014 Panamerican Highway Widening Santiago - Vigui | Panama • Provided design alternatives including 3D models and drawings for intersections • Analyzed the slope stability of critical sections • Construction cost: \$340.0 millions Corredor Turistico La Barca – El Progreso – Tela | Honduras 2014 · Conceived design drawings for roundabouts and urban sections including sidewalks, and bus-stops Provided traffic signs drawings using the MUTCD and local guidelines • Construction cost: \$120.0 millions Slope Stabilization Studies 53 km | Panama 2014 • Interpreted the slope stability analysis results Examined ground improvement alternatives • Construction cost: \$0.4 millions Amador Causeway Widening | Panama 2014 • Assisted with the geometric design of roundabouts • Participated in the creation of the digital terrain model • Assisted with the modeling of critical sections for embankments stability analysis • Construction cost: \$95.0 millions 2012 Coastal Beltway | Panama · Developed design drawings for roadways including roundabouts, marine viaducts, and interchanges • Construction cost: \$ 45 millions Professional Societies ASCE: American Society of Civil Engineers 2022 - Present ITE: Institute of Transportation Engineers 2019 - Present References

Lily Elefteriadou, PhD: Barbara Goldsby Professor, University of Florida

Aurora Izquierdo: Civil Structural Engineer II, WSP Juliana Canas: Senior Advisor, First Climate

Julio Aysa: Env./Social and Governance Lead Officer, IDB

elefter@ce.ufl.edu Aurora.Izquierdo@wsp.com juliana.canas-vanegas@firstclimate.com jaysa71@yahoo.com.mx